(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-11T05:21:49.942472",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
12時を少し過ぎる頃
Just past midnight...
ああ…
Ah...
残酷なMonster
A cruel monster.
月明かり草木眠る頃
In the moonlight when the plants sleep...
ああ…
Ah...
萌ゆる
Blooming...
君の叫びで
Awakened by your scream,
僕は目覚める
I open my eyes.
今宵の闇へ
Into tonight's darkness,
君をとざす Monster
locking you away, Monster.
凍りつく夜が創り出す
Created by the freezing night,
We are 君の後ろ Who?
We are behind you, who?
気付いたときはもう閉じ込める Monster
By the time you notice, trapped by the monster,
逃げ場はない
there's no escape.
Just one 君の手を
Just one, your hand,
Two 愛の手を
Two, a loving hand,
Three, Four & Five 抱いて眠りたい
Three, Four & Five, I want to hold you and sleep.
夜が明けるまで 近くにいよ
Stay close to me until dawn breaks.
僕の記憶が 全て消えても
Even if all my memories fade away,
生まれ変わったら また君を探す
If I am reborn, I will search for you once more.
見かけじゃなくて ここを抱いて
Hold me here, not just for how I look.
満月の夜 君を見つけた モンスター
On a full moon night, I found you, Monster.
扉のない部屋には 迷い込む
I wander into a room with no doors,
足音が徐々に近くなり
Footsteps gradually drawing closer.
息も凍える 止められない 怖がらせたい
Breath freezing, unstoppable, I want to scare you.
だけど本当は 君が好きなんだ
But the truth is, I'm in love with you.
朝が見えるまで 隣にいよ
Stay by my side until the morning light appears.
一万年の愛を叫ぼう
Let's shout out a love of ten thousand years.
生まれ変わっても また君を探す モンスター
Even if I'm reborn, I'll search for you again, Monster.
12時を少し過ぎる頃
Just a little past midnight,
突き刺さり草臥れる頃
When it pierces deep and wears me out,
君の涙で
Through your tears,
僕は目覚める 今宵の闇へ 君を連れ出す
I awaken and lead you into tonight's darkness.
僕の記憶が 全て消えても
Even if all my memories fade away,
生まれ変わったら また君を探す
If I am reborn, I will search for you once more.
見かけじゃなくて ここを抱いて
Hold me here, not just for how I look.
満月の夜 君を見つけた モンスター
On a full moon night, I found you, Monster.
モンスター
Monster
曖昧ディスコミュニケーション まさしく狂気の花
Vague miscommunication, truly a flower of madness.
泣きそうに悲しそうに あなたに伝えたい
Looking like you're about to cry, looking so sad, I want to tell you.
愛のRE:ラブユー それは魔法の言葉
Love's RE: Love You, that is a magic word.
消えそうに優しそうに あなたに伝えたい
Fading away so gently, I want to tell you.
幸せな蝶になったって
Even if I became a happy butterfly,
瞬で宙に頓挫して
Stumbling into the sky in a flash,
ならば願い託して
Then entrust your wish,
受け止めで認めて
Accept it, acknowledge it.
揺れるファイアー 叫ぶフライハイ あたし染まれれば
Swaying fire, screaming fly high, if I can be dyed in you,
二人の幸せとか 積もる情熱をあげるわ
I'll give you our happiness and piling passion.
揺れるファイアー 叫ぶフライハイ 闇を照らすのさ
Swaying fire, screaming fly high, illuminating the darkness.
怒りと憎しみさえも 届く衝撃をくれるから
Even anger and hatred give an impact that reaches me.
一人は耐えうるものね
One person can endure it,
痛いは愛することね
Pain is just loving,
ふたりは今を生きる
The two of us live in the present.
ファイアー 揺れるファイアー 二人染まれれば
Fire, swaying fire, if the two of us can be dyed in it.
夢見心地のあなたに その瞳幸あれ
May your dreaming eyes be blessed with happiness.
曖昧ディスコミュ まるで狂気の花
One vague, misjudged view, like a faint flower gone insane
泣きそうに悲しそうに あなたに伝えたい
Seeming so blue, like it'll cry too, I just wanna tell you someday
愛のRE:ラブユー それは 魔法の言葉
Love's own re: love you, that's a great magic word I want to say
消えそうに優しそうに あなたに伝えたい
Kind and so true, like it'll fade through, I just wanna tell you some way
幸せな蝶になったって 瞬きで穹に頓挫して
If I became a butterfly, so free, I'd fall into the sky at once
ならば願い託して 受け付けて認めて
Every little wish I had then, accept and carry them, hold them again
揺れるファイアー 叫ぶフライハイ 私染まれれば
The swayin' fire, it's screamin', "Fly high", if I could wallow in that dye
二人の幸せとか 積もる 情熱をあげるわ
I'll give you passion that'll grow with time, see the happiness thrive
揺れるファイアー 叫ぶフライハイ 闇を照らすのだ
The swayin' fire, it's screamin', "Fly high", it's always lighting up the night
怒りと憎しみさえも 届く 衝動をくれるから
'Cuz deep inside, now even hate I find, makes an impact I can't hide
一人は耐えうるものね 痛みは愛することね
Some way, somehow, one can bear it alone, this pain is how loving will show
二人は今を生きる
We're here right now, though we don't even know how far we'll go
ファイアー 揺れるファイアー 二人染まれれば
Fire, the swayin' fire, if we could wallow in their dye
夢見心地のあなたに その瞳幸あれ
With every second that you're dreaming at night, may every pleasure fill your eyes
揺れるファイアー 燃えるフライアウェい 駆け足で行きましょう
The swayin' fire, burning flyaway, we're running into the flames
愛と涙のドラマに その命突き出せ
Give your everything, including your life, to all the drama love provides
受け付けて認めて
Accept and carry them, hold them again
揺れるファイアー 叫ぶフライハイ
The swayin' fire, it's screamin', "Fly high"
二人の幸せとか 描く 情熱をあげるわ
The happiness we have, our passion will grow
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
まずは2曲お届けしました。姫たちもありがとうございます。
First, I've delivered two songs. Thank you to the princesses as well.
ということで、6周年ライブへようこそ！わーい！
And with that, welcome to the 6th anniversary live! Yay!
ついに6周年になりました。えっと、みなさんのコメントを読みたいと思います。
It's finally our 6th anniversary. Um, I'd like to read everyone's comments.
パチパチ、スイッチゃ、え、かっこいいありがとう、かっこよかったありがとう。
Clap clap, Suic-chan, cool, thank you, it was cool, thank you.
そう、かっこよさ全開でね、あの、一番最初は「王様」をやらしていただきました。姫たちよ！
Right, with maximum coolness, right at the start, I got to play the king. You princesses!
そして今日は、6周年でもあるんですけれど、と、同時に、誕生日でもあるんです！わーい！
And today is not only our 6th anniversary, but also my birthday! Yay!
だ！18歳になりました。ついに18歳になりましたよみなさん！
I'm 18 years old now. I've finally turned 18, everyone!
わあ、えっと、18.6歳か。いやあ、時の流れは本当に早いですね。
Wow, um, 18.6 years old, huh. Boy, time really flies.
今日までね、活動を続けられてるのもみなさんのおかげで本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you truly to all of you for allowing me to continue my activities up until today.
最初のね2曲は、舞踏会をイメージして、やってみました。
The first two songs, I tried doing them with a ball in mind.
7年目の最初を飾る素敵なライブにしようと思ってますので、今日は楽しんでいってください！
I plan to make it a wonderful live to decorate the start of the 7th year, so please enjoy yourselves today!
そしてみなさん、重大告知その1としてですね、匂わせツイートをしたと思うんですけど
And everyone, as major announcement #1, I'm sure I made a hinting tweet...
分かるかな？ね？分かるよね？何が変わったのか。
Do you get it? Right? You know, right? What changed.
と、わかる？ん？ん？お？んーんーんー
So, do you get it? Hm? Hm? Oh? Hmm...
あれ、あんまわかんない？もしかして。
Huh, you don't really get it? Could it be.
わかんないな。髪切った？え、いやいやいやいや、あの、ちょっとメイクをちょっと変えてみたんだよね。
I don't get it. Did you cut your hair? No no no no, um, I tried changing my makeup a bit.
新しい化粧品にしてみたんだけどね。ね、あの、まつ毛とかね、新しいマスカラにしてみたんだけどね。はい、ウインク。
I tried using new cosmetics. My eyelashes, I tried using new mascara. Right, wink.
どう？え？シャンプー変えた？いや、シャンプーは一緒。
How is it? Eh? Did you change your shampoo? Nah, the shampoo is the same.
シャンプーは一緒なの。わかんねえな、わか、え？そんな...
The shampoo is the same. I don't get it, wa-, huh? Like that...
ま、ということで、え、メイクがちょっとだけ新しくなりました！
Well, with that, um, my makeup has become just a little bit newer!
え、この新しいメイクで、撮影会をですね、このライブが終わったあと面会でやりますので、みなさんぜひ見に来てくださいね。
Um, with this new makeup, we'll be holding a photo session meeting after this live finishes, so everyone please come check it out.
あと、なんか台本が更新されたぞ。トレンド1位なんですか？トレンド1位になったの？おー、ありがとうございます！やった！
Also, it looks like the script was updated. Is it #1 on trends? Did it become #1 on trends? Oh, thank you very much! Yay!
ありがとうみんな！いや、まだまだつぶやいてください。
Thank you everyone! Well, please keep tweeting.
もうトレンド1位より上を目指しましょう。
Let's aim even higher than #1 on trends.
そして、え、重大告知1つめは このメイクがちょっと変わったようだったんですけど、まだ、まだ重大告知ありますのでね、ぜひ最後まで見てくださいね。
And, um, major announcement #1 was that this makeup seemed to have changed a bit, but there are still more major announcements, so please be sure to watch until the end.
ではそろそろ、え、次、次の曲いっちゃってもいいかな？いいかな？
Well then, soon, um, next, would it be okay if we went ahead to the next song? Is that okay?
それでは参りたいと思います。次の曲は激しめでいきましょう！
Then I'd like to proceed. Let's go with an intense song for the next one!
弾丸込めた小銃を 僕は片手に持っている
I hold a fully loaded rifle in one hand
弾丸詰めた小銃を
In one hand I hold a loaded rifle,
僕は片手に持っている
as I make my way toward you.
震えた君のいる場所へ 足を早め向かっている
My steps quicken toward the place where you tremble.
チクタク 針をチクタクと
Tick-tock, the clock ticks away,
留まる気配もなく進んでいく
pressing forward without a hint of stopping.
誰の温度もない部屋で
In a room with no one's warmth,
冷え切った手を伸ばしている
I reach out my frozen hands.
塞いだ僕がいる場所は
Where I am, locked away,
誰にもわからない
nobody knows.
チクタク 針をチクタクと
Tick-tock, the clock ticks away,
終わりと始まりの境目
at the boundary of end and beginning.
チクタク 針をチクタクと
Tick-tock, the clock ticks away,
全て重なった
as everything overlapped.
閉口して僕は待っていた
I sat there in silence and waited
笑えるほどの悲しみを
for a sadness so deep it made me smile.
閉口して僕は待っていた
I sat there in silence and waited
涙するほどの幸福も
for a happiness that brought me to tears.
誰の温度もない部屋で
In a room with no one's warmth,
冷え切った手を伸ばしている
I reach out my frozen hands.
塞いだ僕がいる場所は
Where I am, locked away,
誰にもわからない
nobody knows.
チクタク 針をチクタクと
Tick-tock, the clock ticks away,
溜め息溜め息の日々を
through days of endless sighs.
チクタク 針をチクタクと
Tick-tock, the clock ticks away,
進まない僕を
at a me who cannot move forward.
チクタク 針をチクタクと
Tick-tock, the clock ticks away,
責め立てるように
as if trying to punish me.
チクタク 針をチクタクと
Tick-tock, the clock ticks away,
全て重なった
as everything overlapped.
閉口して僕は待っていた
I sat there in silence and waited
薄暗い部屋 一人きり
all alone in a dim room.
閉口して僕は待っていた
I sat there in silence and waited
ドアを穿るその音を
for the sound of breaking down the door.
閉口して僕は待っていた
I sat there in silence and waited
薄暗い部屋 一人きり
all alone in a dim room.
閉口して僕は待っていた
I sat there in silence and waited
もう怯えることはないよ
there is nothing to fear anymore.
弾丸詰めた小銃を持って 固く閉じ込められたドアを穿った
Holding a loaded rifle, I smashed down the tightly locked door.
吸い付いた銃口が跳ねて 昨日の僕を貫いた
The clinging barrel recoiled and pierced the me of yesterday.
おやすみ その絶望を受け取って
"Good night," accepting that despair,
明日への僕は歩き始めた
I began to walk toward tomorrow.
また今夜 待ち合わせよう
Let's meet again tonight.
ねえねえ この世界を
Hey, hey, I want to turn this world
どこかでひっくり返したくて
upside down somewhere.
せいぜい 時間なんてありはしないが
At best, we don't have much time,
まあまあ そんなんで少年少女揃いまして
but well, boys and girls gathered like this
謳い始めた会心劇さ
and started singing this triumphant drama.
天才で人外で横暴な
A genius, inhuman, and overbearing
最低で最高な相棒さ
worst yet best partner.
シンプルで明快な考えが
Won't such a simple and clear thought
僕をここで目覚ませてくれないか
wake me up right here?
今 この身を持って
Now, taking this body and lifting the weight,
重石を取って 君にだけにしかできない事なんだ
there are things only you can do.
ここにいないでくれ
Please don't be here.
慰めなんていらないよ
I don't need any comfort.
荒地になってしまわぬように
So it doesn't turn into a wasteland,
その名を隠して ここに現れたのさ
you hid your name and appeared here.
のさばってる奴らを
Those who run rampant—
探して抉って 嘲っては泣いてい
search for them, dig them out, mock and cry.
ああ しょうがないな
Ah, it can't be helped.
勝手にやってな 文句ばかり
Do as you like, just full of complaints.
否定したって何したって 誰かのせいにしたって
No matter how you deny, or blame someone else,
ああ フラッシュバックして 小心者に眩暈がして
Ah, flashing back, a coward feels dizzy,
感情も根性も 腐ってしまいました
and both emotions and grit have rotted away.
思い出したくない一日は
A day I don't want to remember
ここに吐いていってしまえよ
just spit it out right here.
いらんもんなんて捨てていって
Throw away whatever you don't need
僕をここで壊してくれないか
and break me right here, won't you?
今 別のを待って
Now, waiting for another,
口を結んで 染み付いた夜の傷が癒せないのなら
closing my mouth, if the ingrained scars of night won't heal,
涙は見せないで
don't show your tears.
こんな気高さはいらないよ
I don't need such nobility.
全て失ってしまわぬように
So we don't lose everything,
変わらぬものがここにあるとするならば
if something unchanging exists right here,
夜が明ける前に
before the night breaks,
そうさ行ってしまえと
just go, that's right.
白と黒の色のない世界に溢れた
Overflowing into a world without black and white,
愛も全部ないよその世界に溺れた
drowning in a world with no love at all.
心の鬼は決して許してはくれないから
The demon in my heart will never forgive me,
影は伸び切って日は落ちきって
shadows stretch out completely, the sun sets entirely,
明日を迎えることが許されたなら
and if we are permitted to welcome tomorrow,
救われてたのかな それでも僕は
would I have been saved? Even so, I—
今 この身を持って
Now, taking this body...
救われてたかな
Was I saved...?
それでも僕は
Even so, I...
今この身を持って 重石を取って
Now, taking off the heavy weights with this very body,
君にだけにしかできないことはなんだ
what is the only thing that only you can do?
ここにいないでくれ
Don't be here.
慰めなんていらないよ
I don't need any comfort.
荒地になってしまわぬように
So that it doesn't turn into a wasteland,
その名を隠してここに現れたのさ
hiding that name, I appeared right here.
のさばってる奴らを
The ones acting up high and mighty—
探って抉って 嘲っては泣いて
search, gouge out, sneer and cry.
その小さな勇気が
That small courage
僕の胸を焦がすから
burns my chest.
渇いた風が 心通り抜ける
A thirsty wind blows right through my heart,
溢れる想い 連れ去ってほしい
washing away the overflowing feelings.
2人の影 何気ない会話も
Even our two shadows and casual conversations
嫉妬してる 切なくなる これが恋なの?
make me jealous, making me ache—is this love?
あなたしか見えなくなって 想い育てくばかり
I can only see you, just nurturing these feelings.
苦しくて 見せかけの笑顔も作れないなんて
It hurts so much I can't even put on a fake smile.
満ちては欠ける 想いが今 愛しくて溢れ出すの
Feelings that wax and wane overflow with love right now.
舞い踊る風の中で 巡り逢えたこの奇跡が
In the dancing wind, this miracle of meeting you
遥かな大地を越えて あなたと未来へ歩きたいの
crosses a distant land, and I want to walk with you toward the future.
君だけを想う気持ち 伝えられる勇気が 私にあれば
If only I had the courage to convey these feelings of thinking only of you...
切ない夜に さよならできる
I could say goodbye to this painful night,
願いを込めて wish my love 踏み出す力ください
putting my wish into "wish my love," give me the strength to take a step forward.
かえでさん、今日は来てくれてありがとうございます！
Kaede-san, thank you so much for coming today!
お招きいただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for having me!
シンデレラガールズの高垣楓です。
I'm Kaede Takagaki from Cinderella Girls.
すいせいさん、デビュー6周年、そしてお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Suisei-san, congratulations on your 6th debut anniversary and your birthday!
かえでさんと「こいかぜ」一緒に歌えて、本当に嬉しいです！
I'm so happy I got to sing "Koikaze" together with Kaede-san!
私もすいせいさんとご一緒できて、すごく嬉しかったです。
I was also so happy to be able to join you, Suisei-san.
とっても素敵な歌声で…ええ、ありがとうございます！
With such a wonderful singing voice... um, thank you so much!
かえでさんのことがずっと応援していて大好きだったので、今回のコラボができたことが夢みたいです。
I've always supported and loved Kaede-san, so it's like a dream that this collaboration actually happened.
ありがとうございます。こんなお祝いの場に呼んでいただけて、こちらこそ光栄ですよ。
Thank you so much. I'm the one who is honored to be invited to such a celebratory occasion.
今回このコラボが実現したのは、私たちのコラボ曲もあるからなんですよね？
The reason this collaboration happened this time is also because we have our collaboration song, right?
ええ！お互いの良さが現れた、とても素敵な楽曲になりましたね。
Yes! It turned out to be such a wonderful song that highlights both of our strengths.
皆さんもぜひ楽しんでください！
Everyone, please enjoy it as well!
それでは、聞いてください。せーの、ジュビリー！
Now then, please listen. Ready, set, Jubilee!
始まるよジュビリーねえ
The jubilee is about to begin, hey...
超新星と行進しよう
Let's march with the supernova
ジュビリー 作詞・作曲・編曲：TAKU INOUE
Jubilee / Lyrics, Music, Arrangement: TAKU INOUE
ずっと待っているフレーズを確かめて
Checking the phrase we've been waiting for,
目を合わせた きっと太陽は
our eyes met. I'm sure the sun...
いまごろ夢の中
is dreaming right about now.
ようこそパレードへ
Welcome to the parade!
チケットはいらない
You don't need a ticket.
君がそこにいる 音楽が始まる
You're right there, and the music begins.
高らかにホーンズアップ
Horns up, loud and clear,
めくるめくようなフレーズは一時のトロイメライ
a dizzying phrase is a fleeting reverie.
鮮やかなトランペット 夜空をわたって 照れ屋の月さえ
A brilliant trumpet crosses the night sky, making even the shy moon...
顔を出すんだ
show its face.
さながら僕らは天の川
As if we are the Milky Way,
宇宙までいこうぜドラムメジャー
a drum major heading all the way to space!
星の街 恋の風
The city of stars, the wind of love,
出逢いは音楽になってまた咲く銀河系のすみっこで
encounters turn into music and bloom once again in the corner of the galaxy.
同じ呼吸と 同じハーモニー
The same breathing, the same harmony.
ほら ほら 奇跡はここにある
Look, look, miracles are right here!
始まるよジュビリー さあ 上昇気流に乗せて Let the music swing and sing
Let the Jubilee begin! Now, catch the updraft—Let the music swing and sing!
星くずのチューニング いてんこせこすドラムライン もっと
Tuning stardust, drum line keeping the beat, even more...
遠く 遠く 終わらないジュビリー
further, further, an endless jubilee!
さあ 自由にトライのベルを鳴らせ Let the music swing and sing 探しに行こうぜ
Come, ring the bell of freedom! Let the music swing and sing, let's go search for it!
スイメーしよう 新星と行進しよう ずっと 遠く 遠く
Let's Suimei, let's march with the supernova, far, far away!
今夜 君の涙と
Tonight, with your tears
僕の弱さが 出会って出会って
and my weakness meeting each other,
歌になればいいなんて 笑う
wishing it could turn into a song, I smile.
間違いじゃないでしょうスコール 未完成な夜を救いたいから
It can't be a mistake, a squall, because I want to save this unfinished night.
ほら まだ奇跡よ 僕らの奇跡を
Look, still a miracle—our miracle,
祈って歌うよ 祈って歌うよ
I'll pray and sing, I'll pray and sing!
続けようジュビリー さあ 乾杯よりも先に
Let's keep the jubilee going! Now, even before a toast—
Let the music swing and sing ありえない瞬間
Let the music swing and sing, an impossible moment!
速度 革命前夜 まくって もっと
Speed, the eve of revolution, turning pages, even more...
遠く 遠く 終わらないジュビリー
further, further, an endless jubilee!
最高潮かながれ Let the music swing and sing 探しに行こうぜ
Reaching the climax, let the music swing and sing, let's go search for it!
スイメーしよう 新星と行進しよう ずっと 遠く
Let's Suimei, let's march with the supernova, far...
遠く 君と遠くまで
far away, with you, all the way into the distance!
はーい！
Ha-i!
ということで、えー高垣楓さんと新曲ジュビリー、そして高垣楓さんのソロ曲「恋風」をお届けさせていただきました。
And with that, um, we delivered the new song "Jubilee" with Kaede Takagaki-san, as well as Kaede Takagaki-san's solo song "Koikaze".
本当に、本当に夢のような時間で、本当に楓さんありがとうございました！楓さん！ありがとうございました！
Truly, it was such a dreamlike time. Thank you so much, Kaede-san! Kaede-san, thank you so much!
本当に指の先まですごいパフォーマンスがお綺麗で、それに並り立てるようにと頑張って踊らせていただきました。
Truly, her performance was so gorgeous down to her fingertips, and I did my best to dance alongside her.
えーぜひとも、ぜひともね、この後の重大告知も皆さん心して、心してくださいね！それでは
Um, please, everyone, prepare yourselves for the major announcements coming up after this! Well then,
では、重大告知、2つ目告知しちゃいたいと思います！
Now, I'd like to make the second major announcement!
こちら！
Here it is!
今回、初披露させていただいた星街すいせい、高垣楓によるコラボ楽曲「ジュビリー」が、3月23日15:00よりデレステのゲーム内イベントにて登場します！
The collaboration song "Jubilee" by Hoshimachi Suisei and Kaede Takagaki, which was premiered today, will appear in an in-game event in Deresute starting March 23 at 15:00!
イベントの報酬や、報酬Sレアカードに私、星街すいせいが登場します！なんてかわいいの、私も楓さんもありがとう！
I, Hoshimachi Suisei, will appear as an event reward and reward S-Rare card! How cute, thank you to both me and Kaede-san!
そして、同じく明日3月23日15:00より、星街すいせいと高垣楓がSSレアアイドルとして登場するコラボガチャが開催です！
Also, starting tomorrow, March 23 at 15:00, a collaboration gacha featuring Hoshimachi Suisei and Kaede Takagaki as SS-Rare idols will be held!
衣装は私たち二人のためにデザインされた特別な衣装になっていますので、ぜひデレステでゲットしてみてください！本当にいろんな関係者の方々のお力のおかげでこのような夢のような衣装が叶っております本当にありがとうございます。
The outfits are specially designed for the two of us, so please try to get them in Deresute! Thanks to everyone involved, this dream-like outfit has become a reality, thank you so much.
そして、えー第2回デレステコラボ配信が決定しました！3月26日20:00から私のチャンネルで行う予定ですのでぜひ見に来てください。
And, uh, the 2nd Deresute collab stream has been decided! It's scheduled to take place on my channel on March 26 at 20:00, so please come check it out.
えー先ほど発表したコラボ楽曲「ジュビリー」のMVや、コラボガチャで登場するSSレアなども紹介します！えーそのほか第1回配信で遊びきれなかったライブなども遊んでいくのでお楽しみに。
Uh, I'll also introduce the MV for the collaboration song "Jubilee" announced earlier, and the SS-Rare cards appearing in the gacha! And we'll also play some live performances we couldn't finish in the 1st stream, so look forward to it.
そして最後！コラボ楽曲「ジュビリー」が3月24日日曜日0時に各音楽サービスでの配信が決定しました！
And finally! The release of the collaboration song "Jubilee" on various music services has been decided for Sunday, March 24 at 0:00!
そう、作詞作曲編曲は我らがTAKU INOUE！井のたくさんです！ぜひ配信でもたくさん聞いてください！
Yes, lyrics, composition, and arrangement by none other than our own TAKU INOUE! So many Inus! Please listen to it a lot on streaming!
はい、ありがとうございました！立て続けのデレステ情報でしたが皆さんぜひ明日からイベント、そしてガチャが始まりますのでぜひぜひデレステで遊んでみてくださいね！
Yep, thank you very much! It was a lot of Deresute info back-to-back, but the event and gacha start tomorrow, so please go play Deresute!
ということで、えー次の曲に行きたいと思います。テイチね。テイチに戻って、それでは後半戦も盛り上がっていきましょう！
With that said, uh, I'd like to move on to the next song. Back to Teichi. Let's get hyped for the second half!
到着だ 今宵の雑踏はまるで プログレみたいなビートで踊ってる
We've arrived. Tonight's bustle dances to a beat like progressive rock.
路地裏ネオンのマーケット
A market of back-alley neon.
見慣れない文字と言葉をいなして 秘め巡りにコードそっとかわして
Deflecting unfamiliar letters and words, quietly dodging codes on a hidden tour.
この街が今日のターゲット
This city is today's target.
視界は悪いな 逆光
Visibility is poor, backlight.
奇怪な機構の人口ブラックホール
An artificial black hole with bizarre mechanics.
音色を仕込んだ薬莢
A cartridge loaded with timbre.
あれなら二つで十分
If it's that, two is enough.
力んだ呼吸戻して
Regain your strained breathing.
ニキータくらい済ました顔で シリンダーを出して装填
With a face as calm as Nikita, pull out the cylinder and load.
スポットライトみたいに
Like a spotlight,
照準をさらって
sweep the sights.
さあ始めようか
Now then, shall we begin?
すべて変える 4カウント
Four counts to change everything.
終わりのない夜をあげる 合図して
I'll give you a never-ending night, give the signal.
世界の秘密暴くよ ずっと響いてるSOS
Exposing the world's secrets, an SOS keeps echoing.
退屈なスパイラル 3つ数えてアンロックで
A boring spiral, count to three and unlock,
反撃だ
it's a counterattack!
光の海に潜って 歌詞で繋いでいく点と線
Dive into a sea of light, connecting dots and lines with lyrics.
カオティックな音に乗せて
Riding on chaotic sounds,
世界の秘密暴くよ 今日はネグラでポレ
exposing the world's secrets, let's party at the hideout today.
散々食いてぇお高くとまったドアもアンロックで
Even that snobbish door you've wanted to bite into, unlock it and
迎撃だ
intercept!
光の海を泳いで 僕のフレーズとプレクトラム
Swim through the sea of light, my phrases and plectrum.
カオティックな音で踊って
Dance to the chaotic sound,
さあ灰になるまで
come on, until we turn to ash,
ハイになるまで
until we get high.
静寂は不穏な空気を孕んで この部屋の闇をそっと隠している
Silence breeds an uneasy atmosphere, quietly concealing the darkness of this room.
右に罠 左側 裏に3名
A trap on the right, left side, three people in the back.
キッチュな耳鳴り ソリストをもっと練習しといて
Kitsch ringing in the ears, solist needs to practice more.
狂いに狂ったチューニング 天鵝絨の奥の醜態
Madly crazed tuning, the ugliness deep within the velvet.
聞こえてるずっと192kHzで
I've been hearing it constantly at 192kHz.
過剰な意匠の空砲
A blank shot of excessive design.
ひるんできている場合じゃないの
This is no time to be flinching.
リロードいらずの銃口
A muzzle that needs no reloading.
思考を拒んだ人造スナイパー 身の程知らずでいいさ
An artificial sniper that rejects thought, it's fine to bite off more than you can chew.
アリーナに立って 照準をさらって
Stand in the arena, sweep the sights.
さあどうしようか 負け犬のポーカー それでもまだ笑ったままで
Now what should we do, a loser's poker, still keeping a smile.
オールイン
All in!
合図して 世界の秘密暴くよ 1、2ラタッタッタッタ
Give the signal, exposing the world's secrets, one, two, ratattatta.
退屈なスパイラル 3つ数えてアンロックで
A boring spiral, count to three and unlock,
流星を纏って
wrapped in shooting stars,
迎えるショーダウン 逆転ロイヤルストレートフラッシュ
welcoming the showdown, a comeback royal straight flush.
カオティックな音に乗せて 世界を一つさらうよ
Riding on chaotic sounds, sweeping up the whole world.
喝采カーテンコールで 錆び付いている難攻不落のドアもアンロックで バイバイさ
With an applause curtain call, unlocking even the rusty impregnable door, bye-bye.
最低のタイワニ トグロを巻いて
Winding around the worst kind of conversation,
剥き出して
baring our fangs,
救世を求めて 向かう招待 逆転
Heading toward an invitation seeking salvation, inverted,
ロイヤルフェタス
Royal fetus,
カオティックな音に のせて
Riding on the chaotic sound.
アイズでスカイを一つにしようよ
Let's make the eyes and sky one,
カイトバックカーテンコールで
with a kite-back curtain call!
寒くいてを なんかプラクノザモ ハノクテ
With a chilly, somewhat pragmatic desire,
ハイウェイ タイムスクイの 水を泳いで 僕のブレスト フェックスラム
swimming through the water of highway time-squeezes, my breast-fed phantasm.
ハイウェイで アノゼ 走って
Running along the highway,
カオティックな音で 踊って
dancing to the chaotic sound.
ハイにナマデを
Raw at the high.
潮れた夜に 流れざったメロディー
In a withered night, a flowing melody,
絡まってるのに
even though they're intertwined,
愛はほどけていく
love keeps untangling.
いつだってそうに 一杯したがってるのに
Always wanting so much to play it safe,
fake face dance music ユアゲマデ踊って
fake face dance music, dancing until your game is over.
いつだって情緒不安定 ないことあることも言っちゃってんだ
Always emotionally unstable, sometimes saying things that aren't true,
行き場のないこの世界では 稀に見かける愛を信じ続けてる
in this world with nowhere to go, continuing to believe in a rare kind of love.
朝食がてらのバカバカしい ニュースで誰かが笑ってた
Someone was laughing at a ridiculous news story over breakfast.
その時からなのか 知ってる世界じゃなくなっていた
Ever since then, the world I knew ceased to exist.
本当におかしな人生ね それでも愛した運命で
Such a truly strange life, yet it's the destiny I loved.
あなたにこの心をハイジャックされた
My heart was hijacked by you.
跳ねたテンポに 重ねるメロディー 絡まってるのに
A melody layered on a bouncing tempo, even though they're intertwined,
愛はほどけていく
love keeps untangling.
いつだってそうに 心配しちゃってるふり
Always pretending to be worried,
浮ついた心までも聖人とか さらけ出して
exposing even a fickle heart as if it were a saint's.
愛を見つけて これが本当に幸せなんだろうなとか思ったり
Finding love and thinking, "Is this what true happiness feels like?"
可愛くなるため頑張ったり そのたびフラッシュバックバック浴びてくまに
Trying hard to look cute, getting flashbacks over and over,
失望感にせがまれて守るとか 君しか見てないとか言われても
pestered by disappointment, even if you tell me you protect me or only look at me,
信用できないな
I just can't trust you.
呼びかけてるのに あの子に夢中で
Even though I'm calling out, you're obsessed with that girl,
絡まってるのに 愛がすり抜けていく
intertwined, yet love slips right through.
チクタク チクタクと 時計の針だけが流れてく 置いてかないでね
Tick-tock, tick-tock, only the clock hands flow past, don't leave me behind!
本当は夢見た少女そう 相対的現実的には期待は損で
Truly a dreamy girl, relatively and realistically speaking, expectations are a loss,
パットなエンディング 不気味なそっちのタイミング
a sudden ending, that creepy timing of yours.
従いなんてさ 信じてたのに 本命じゃなくて
I trusted you like an obedient servant, but I wasn't your true favorite,
浮気女だわ
I'm just a cheating woman.
潮れた夜に 流れざるメロディー
In a withered night, a flowing melody,
絡まってるのに
even though they're intertwined,
愛はほどけていく
love keeps untangling.
シンデレラストーリー とって一切違ってるのに
A Cinderella story, completely different from how it should be,
fake face dance music 嘘まみれに踊ろう
fake face dance music, let's dance covered in lies.
オレンジの太陽を追いかけてきたの 手の中にあるのは 赤いビー玉ね
I've been chasing the orange sun, what I hold in my hand is a red marble.
ねぇあとちょっとだけね それがいたくて なごりりさんだる かかとを鳴らす
Hey, just a little bit more, because it hurts, my sandals click their heels.
いついつまでも 一人で歩くの くるくまわって
Forever and ever, walking alone, spinning around and around.
すりすり抜けてく 孤独のこれまで 鳴らしたり寂しさで
Slipping right through to the depths of loneliness, making sounds or feeling lonely,
すのろくにいるの 君にもう一度あいたくて
staying in that groove, wanting to meet you one more time.
映画でいうなら 最後の場面
If it were a movie, it'd be the final scene,
終わりたくないよ スローにして
I don't want it to end, make it slow.
こんな当たり前が大事ってことに なんで今気付いてるの？
Why am I only realizing now how precious everyday things are?
二人浜辺を 歩いていく
The two of us walk along the beach,
夕陽の赤さに 溶けながら
melting into the red of the setting sun.
エンドロールには早すぎる
It's too soon for the end roll.
潮の匂いが こんなにも
The scent of the tides
切なくないものだったなんて
never felt so painful before.
気になるけれど 君の過去には 触れないことで 保たれてた
I'm curious about your past, but leaving it untouched kept us going.
そうで抱き合って 追いかけっこしてさ 失うのが怖くなって
Embracing and chasing each other, getting scared of losing you.
着飾った街並みさまよって まつ毛に風を 受けながら
Wandering through dressed-up streets, taking the wind on my eyelashes.
エンドロールには早すぎる イルミネーションが にじんでく
It's too soon for the end roll, the illuminations are blurring.
世界の果ては ここにある
The end of the world is right here.
こんな当たり前が大事ってことに なんで今気付いてるの？
Why am I only realizing now how precious everyday things are?
おかまいなしに めぐりくる 季節が僕を 追い越しても
Even if the seasons keep passing by without a care, overtaking me,
エンドロールには早すぎる 君のくしゃみが 聞きたいよ
it's too soon for the end roll, I want to hear you sneeze.
意外なオチに 賭けている
I'm betting on a surprising ending.
パラリパラパラリダッタ...
Parari-para-paralidatta...
君にもう一度 会いたくて 行くには早すぎる
Wanting to see you once more is far too soon.
映画でいうなら 最後の場面 終わりたくないよ スローにして
If it were a movie, it'd be the final scene, I don't want it to end, make it slow.
こんな当たり前が大事ってことに なんで今気付いてるの？
Why am I only realizing now how precious everyday things are?
二人浜辺を 歩いていく 夕陽の赤さに 溶けながら
The two of us walk along the beach, melting into the red of the setting sun.
エンドロールには早すぎる
It's too soon for the end roll.
潮の匂いが こんなにも
The scent of the tides
切なくないものだったなんて
never felt so painful before.
数えてみたよ 億劫何回いらないよ
I tried counting, how many times I didn't need this hassle...
見帰りにくから大丈夫
It's okay because it's hard to look back.
コメディックメモリ
Comic memory...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ということで、えー ライブも もう最後に差し掛かってきました。
And with that, the live is already reaching its final moments.
はーい！
Yes!
ではみなさん、えー ラストの告知パートに参りたいと思います。どんだけ告知やねんって感じなんだけれども。
Now everyone, um, we'll move on to the final announcement part. Feels like 'how many announcements are there?!'
あ、その前にちょっとコメント読もうかな。
Ah, before that, let me read some comments.
コメント、ちょっと待って、コメント、えっと、あのそこにあるんだ。
Comments, hold on, comments, um, they're right over there.
うーん、「今来たばっかり！もう終わりか！？」うそでしょ？今来たさん？
Hmm, 'Just got here! Is it already over?!' No way, 'Just got here-san'?
もう44分。
It's already 44 minutes.
はい、えー 早すぎる！まだ来たばっか可愛い。あ！
Right, um, too fast! You just got here, so cute. Ah!
ありがとう！ありがとうコメント！イェーイ！セットリスト神過ぎてありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you for the comments! Yay! The setlist was too god-tier, thank you so much!
ということで、えー 告知やっていきたいと思います。まずはもうすでに出ている情報から参ります。こちら！
So, um, let's do the announcements. First, let's start with information that's already out. Here!
えー、ZOZOTOWNさんとコラボさせていただくことが発表されております！
Um, it's been announced that we're collaborating with ZOZOTOWN!
えー 3月22日、今日のお昼から受注販売が始まっています！
Um, starting today at noon, March 22nd, pre-order sales have begun!
期間は4月12日までですが受注販売なので急がなくても大丈夫のはず。しかし、忘れないようにしてくださいね！
The period is until April 12th, but since it's made-to-order, you shouldn't have to rush. Still, please don't forget!
えー、こちらの商品は受注販売期間が終わったあと再販する予定がないけど可能性はあるとのことです。
Um, for these products, once the pre-order period ends, there are no plans to resell them, though there's a possibility.
えー、どうなるか分かりませんがよろしくお願いします。
Um, we don't know what will happen, but thank you for your support.
そしてこの ZOZOTOWNのジャケットを着た星街すいせい等身大フィギュア、皆さんエキスポで見ててくださいましたか？こちら！
And everyone, did you see the life-sized figure of Hoshimachi Suisei wearing this ZOZOTOWN jacket at the Expo? Here!
こちらの等身大フィギュアが1/7スケールになって発売決定しております！
This life-sized figure has been decided for release as a 1/7 scale figure!
こちらのフィギュアは予約期間は5月31日までですので、お財布に余裕がある方はぜひともごりゅう、ご購入くださいませ。
The pre-order period for this figure is until May 31st, so if your wallet allows, please please purchase it.
えー 5月31日までかと思いきや、3月31日までにご予約すると、さいね先生描き下ろしの特製限定ステッカーももらえますのでぜひチェックしてください。
Um, you might think it's until May 31st, but if you pre-order by March 31st, you also get a special limited sticker illustrated by Saine-sensei, so please check it out.
それでは、えー ZOZOTOWNのアパレルグッズの詳細を見ていきたいと思います。じゃん！
Now then, let's look at the details of the ZOZOTOWN apparel goods. Ta-da!
ま、こんな感じです。えー ジャケット、ベレー帽、ベルト、Tシャツ、グッズセット、そしてクッションになっています。
Well, it looks like this. Um, jacket, beret, belt, T-shirt, goods set, and cushions.
ぜひ買ってね。
Please buy them.
では、えー お次、こちらもエキスポで発表ありましたね。すいちゃんとあの空のなりきりマイクが発売しまーす！
Now, um, next, this was also announced at the Expo. Suichan and Sora's cosplay microphone is going on sale!
はい、こちらおもちゃが今持っているマイクと全く一緒！めちゃくちゃ似てる、違う点で言うとすいちゃんのボイスが入っているっていうところですね。
Yes, this toy is completely identical to the mic I'm holding right now! Super similar, the only difference is that Suichan's voice is included.
えー 詳細は概要欄にあるバンダイさんのXをチェックしてみてください。
For details, check Bandai's X in the description box.
えー では皆さん、
Um, now everyone,
そこまでは知ってるよと
You might know up to that point,
思った皆さん。
everyone,
ここからは初めての情報となります。
from here on, I have some brand new information.
まずは、こちら！
First up is this!
この度これまでリリースしてきました
This time, my previously released
私のアルバムのアナログレコード化が決定しました！
albums have been decided to get vinyl record releases!
アナログレコードって何？と思っている方、
For those wondering what vinyl records are,
あのよく映画とかアニメで出てくる、あのほら古い、あの針を落として、ウィーーーンってあのクラシックが流れる、あのレコードです。あのレコードになります。
you know, in movies and anime, where you drop the needle and it plays classical music? Those records.
そしてなんと、第一弾として私のファーストアルバム「Still Still Stellar」のレコードが
And amazingly, as the first release, the record for my first album "Still Still Stellar"
5月22日に発売することになりました。
will go on sale on May 22nd.
この後21時より各種CDショップにて予約が開始されますので、
Reservations will start at various CD shops from 21:00 today,
概要欄のURLよりぜひご確認ください。
so please check out the URL in the description.
えー、こちらはですね、あのめちゃくちゃ大きなジャケットになっていて、超映えるので、
Um, this one, you know, has a super huge jacket sleeve and looks extremely photogenic,
レコードがお家にないよって方も、ぜひあのコレクションとして手に入れていただければと思います。
so even if you don't have a record at home, I hope you'll get it for your collection.
え、レコードはですね、どうやら
Um, records apparently
製造にすごく時間がかかって、販売数に限りがあるとのことですので、
take a really long time to manufacture, and there's a limit to the number available,
欲しいなっていう方はぜひお早めにご予約ください。
so if you want one, please make your reservation early.
え、スペクターの方に関しても続報をお待ちください。
Um, please look forward to further news regarding "Spector" as well.
そして！めっけめっけ嬉しいことがあるんです。
And! There is something super, super happy.
見て、これ！
Look at this!
カナヘイがける星街すいせいのコラボが決定しました！
A collaboration between Kanahei and Hoshimachi Suisei has been decided!
うわ！うれしい！うれしい！可愛すぎる！大好きなカナヘイさんとね、コラボができるということで、本当に大人たちありがとうございます。
Whoa! Yay! Yay! Too cute! Being able to collaborate with Kanahei-san, whom I love so much—truly, thank you to all the adults.
え、さらに、え、このイラストは今回のコラボのためにカナヘイさんに描き下ろしていただきました！うわ、カナヘイさん、ありがとう、本当に！
And furthermore, this illustration was drawn specially by Kanahei-san for this collaboration! Wow, Kanahei-san, thank you so much!
もうね、あの、私がこのカナヘイのウサギをどれだけ愛しているかというのはね、普段の私の配信やら、あのTwitterやらで分かると思うんですけれどもち、本当に本当に大好きな、え、ウサギちゃんとピスケちゃん、本当にコラボできて嬉しいです。
You know, how much I love Kanahei's rabbit can be seen from my usual streams and Twitter, but I'm truly, truly so happy to be able to collaborate with my beloved Usagi-chan and Pisuke-chan.
え、他にもイラストを描き下ろしてもらっていて、イラストを使ったグッズ企画も進行中です。詳細は後日改めて告知するので、楽しみに待っていてください！
Um, they've drawn other illustrations for me too, and merchandise planning using the illustrations is also underway. Details will be announced later, so please look forward to it!
あーそして！皆さん、待ってたよね、お馴染みの誕生日&活動6周年記念グッズ！はい、バーナーです。
Ah and! Everyone, you've been waiting for it, right? The familiar birthday & 6th anniversary merchandise! Yes, here it is.
こちら今回はこんな感じ。えっとですね、グッズはちょっと推し活っていうものをテーマにしていろいろ作ってみました。ちょっとまずはフルセットからごご紹介、どうぞ。はい。
This time it looks like this. Um, the merchandise was created with the theme of "Oshikatsu" (supporting one's favorite). Let's start by introducing the full set, please. Yes.
こんな感じ、フルセットだとこれが全部買えるよ。え、そして、バラで見ると、はい、B2タペストリー。
Like this, with the full set you can buy all of this. And, looking at them individually, yes, the B2 tapestry.
はい、こんな感じ。ちょっと推し活をしている感じの、え、すいちゃん。
Yes, like this. Suisan looking like she's doing some "oshikatsu".
そして、ランダムハート型缶バッジ。皆様ランダム本当の申し訳ございません。ランダムで本当の申し訳ございません。ランダムです。ランダムです。えっと、今までの周年記念で出したグッズの、え、キービジュアルをハート型の缶バッジにしました。めちゃくちゃ可愛いので、ちょっとハートだとね、板バネ組みにくいかもしれないけどぜひ組んでください。
And, random heart-shaped can badges. Everyone, I'm truly sorry it's random. I'm truly sorry it's random. It's random. It's random. Um, the key visuals of the merchandise released for past anniversary events have been made into heart-shaped can badges. They're super cute, so please try putting them together.
はい、そして次！おでかけすいちゃんぬいぐるみ！え、欲しかったよね？これ絶対欲しかったよね？これは、えー150mm、はい、150mmすいちゃん、あのリハでは15mmって言っちゃいました。えー150mmのすいちゃん、おでかけにすごくぴったり、あのぜひね、いろんなところに連れて行ってあげてください。
Yes, and next! The "Odekake Suichan" plushie! You wanted this, right? You definitely wanted this, right? This is, uh, 150mm—yes, 150mm Suichan. In rehearsal I accidentally said 15mm. Uh, 150mm Suichan is great for going out, so please take her to various places!
そして！2WAY痛バッグで星読み！はい、見覚えがあるんじゃないでしょうか。こちら、えー3月にね、あの同じ誕生日の、え、桜みこさんのほうと、ちょっとお揃いな感じ。まあ、携帯だけね、携帯だけだよ。ちょっとお揃いな感じにしてしまいました。あのぜひこちら使って、あの、痛バッグ、痛バッグ合わせな感じになってるので、あのフロントポケットはクリア素材って書いてあるんでね、クリア素材なんでここに、あの、缶バッジを連ねていただいて、ぜひお使いくださいというものでした。
And! The 2WAY ita-bag for Hoshiyomi! Yes, doesn't it look familiar? This, uh, in March, you know, with Sakura Miko-san who has the same birthday, kind of matching. Well, just the phone, just the phone. I made it into a matching sort of vibe. Uh, please use this, um, it's styled for ita-bag coordination, so since it says the front pocket is clear material, you can line up can badges here and please use it. That's what it is.
あとは、え、フルセットをご購入いただいた方には、こちら箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます。あ、数量限定ではないです。数量限定ではないので、こちら、あの買った方、全員に、フルセット買った方全員についてきます。はい、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いいたします。
And also, for those who purchase the full set, this foil-stamped replica signed cheki-style bromide card comes with it. Ah, it's not limited in quantity. Since it's not limited, this will come with everyone who buys the full set. Yes, please treat it well.
はい、ということで、え、立て続けにちょっと告知をしてまいりましたが、ちょっとね、告知部数が多すぎてみんなついていけてないとかないよね？ついていけてるよね？ついていけてるー！うわあ！うわあ！ビジネスバック、まあまあまあねビジネス定てを略すな、ビジネス停滞を略すなもう。戦争回避、はい、戦争回避です。
Yes, with that, uh, I've made announcements back-to-back, but you guys aren't overwhelmed by too many announcements, right? You're keeping up, right? You're keeping up! Whoa! Whoa! Business bag—well, well, don't abbreviate business regular... don't abbreviate business stagnation anymore. War avoidance, yes, war avoidance.
はい、ということで、えー、なんと
Yes, and with that, um, amazingly...
次の曲で…最後に…わあ、悲しいよ、もっと聴きたいよ。
For the next song... finally... Ah, how sad, I want to hear more.
次の曲が実は 重大告知3つ目、なんです。
The next song is actually the 3rd major announcement.
ということは、そう、新曲！ 新曲を歌う前に…
Which means, yes, a brand new song! Before singing the new song...
ダンサーさーん！ わあーい！
Dancers! Yay!
この5人で今日の新曲、最後の曲をやらせていただきます。
The five of us will perform today's new song, our final piece.
私もちょっと着替えてよろしいですか？ お着替えまいります！
May I go change clothes as well? I'll be right back!
着替えました、可愛いかな？
I've changed. Do I look cute?
では、このお姿でみんな行けますか？
Now then, can everyone go with this look?
それでは聴いてください、新曲「ビビデバ」！
Now please listen, our new song "Bibideba"!
♪
[Music playing]
つまんないデイズも散々ね
Boring days are a real drag,
奇跡願っているだけの人生
a life spent just wishing for miracles.
WATCH ME DO… 呪術秘中
WATCH ME DO... deep within the spellcraft,
トリック無しのマジック
a magic trick with no illusions.
I WANNA BE FREE! だってまだふりだし
I WANNA BE FREE! Because I'm still at square one,
(THE PARTY AIN'T STARTED)
HEY タクシー ちょっと宇宙まで
HEY taxi, take me to outer space!
秒針は音を立てて
The second hand ticks loudly,
夜を急かす 魔物のよう
rushing the night like a monster.
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法
Life is magic that melts in an instant,
それならば駆け抜けて想い通り！
so then run right through it just as you wish!
おしゃまな馬車 飛び乗って
Hop into the sassy carriage,
DRIVIN' あたしは大変身 メイクアップ！
DRIVIN' I undergo a total transformation, makeup!
我儘のままに 輝きに注意注意
Following my selfish whims, watch out for the sparkles—
洒落た街で DANCIN'
DANCIN' in a stylish town.
左様ならグッバイ 劣等感
Farewell and goodbye, feelings of inferiority;
何時かは喝采 クラップオウディエンス 皆々 御唱和あれ！
someday we'll get cheers and a clapping audience, everyone, sing along!
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
混絡がっても仕様が無い ガラスシューズで踊るTONIGHT
Even if it gets messy, it can't be helped, dancing in glass slippers TONIGHT.
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
今夜に明日など無い ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょ？
There's no tonight or tomorrow, so whoever dances freely wins, right?
DANCE! ラリラリホ
DANCE! Lalariho,
どんな問題も解法は一つ
every problem has only one solution.
白紙も正解も間違いも 愛す本当のあたしの理想
Blank pages, correct answers, mistakes—love my true ideal self.
何だか世界は限界の気配がして
Somehow the world feels like it's on the verge of its limit,
ただただ安心じゃ心配
just feeling safe makes me worried.
今すぐ JUMPIN' JUMPIN' OUT
So right now, JUMPIN' JUMPIN' OUT!
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG CHITTY BANG BANG 唯唯諾諾に危機感抱く日々に
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG, in days of docilely harboring a sense of crisis,
ぎりぎり爆発気味 たった今発散してしまおうか
right on the verge of explosion, shall we vent it right now?
まだまだベイビィ巧みに乱射 一発じゃ撃ち足りないわ
Baby, still cleverly shooting away, one shot isn't enough!
ついに導き出した君にアンサー
Finally, an answer for you that I've deduced:
灰に成る迄踊って居よう
let's keep dancing until we turn to ash!
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
おしゃまな馬車 飛び乗って
Hop into the sassy carriage,
DRIVIN' あたしは大変身 メイクアップ！
DRIVIN' I undergo a total transformation, makeup!
我儘のままに 輝きに注意注意
Following my selfish whims, watch out for the sparkles—
洒落た街で DANCIN'
DANCIN' in a stylish town.
左様ならグッバイ 劣等感
Farewell and goodbye, feelings of inferiority;
何時かは喝采 クラップオウディエンス 皆々 御唱和あれ！
someday we'll get cheers and a clapping audience, everyone, sing along!
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
混絡がっても仕様が無い ガラスシューズで踊るTONIGHT
Even if it gets messy, it can't be helped, dancing in glass slippers TONIGHT.
BIBBIDI BOBBIDI BOOWA
今夜に明日など無い ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょ？
There's no tonight or tomorrow, so whoever dances freely wins, right?
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ビビデバ この後MV公開！よろしくお願いします！またねー！
"Bibideba" MV releases right after this! Please look forward to it! See ya!
New single 「ビビデバ」 3/22 24:00 デジタルリリース開始 このあとMVプレミア公開！
New Single "Bibideba" Digital Release on 3/22 at 24:00 - MV Premiere Coming Up Next!
告知 重大 2024.03.22 星街すいせい 6th Anniversary
[Announcement: Hoshimachi Suisei 6th Anniversary on March 22, 2024]